Long day, but a solid successful day.
Um, a lot of moving parts with uh, Venga
coming in late and we think we did a
good job getting them here across the
country. And as far as the, uh, draft
goes, you know, I think it it fell
nicely for us. Uh, Zion Young, uh, a
big, physical, tough, really good both
run and pass defender who we had a
chance to see this year at the Senior
Bowl in person. Talked to several times.
He was here in Baltimore a couple weeks
ago. Really fits what we want to be on
defense. And uh and Jacobe Lane's
another guy uh that came into Baltimore
uh recently, I think within the last 10
days. Uh really, really impressive kid
to talk with. Um you know, large catch
radius, phenomenal hands, big receiver,
uh tested really well at the combine. Uh
just a a kind of player that we haven't
had lately here. I think he offers a
different dynamic. Um, I, you know, I
think you guys probably know, uh, he was
mentored, uh, by Todd Heap, who, uh, we,
we've talked to, I think Todd's son was
Jacob's quarterback, which is kind of a
cool story. And, uh, had the chance to
get Todd in my office with Jacobe on a
Zoom as he was getting on a plane to
come back to Baltimore for the uh,
jersey uh, unveiling. So, that was kind
of cool. So, anyways, it was a good day.
Hey, we addressed some I think some some
significant needs that we had and we're
excited that we've got eight picks
coming up uh tomorrow. Questions?
>> Yeah, Eric, you did mention with with
Todd. I mean, how much because again you
I know you take input everywhere you can
get it, but how much does you know
getting a guy that's known one of your
prospects since he was like 13 years
old? How much does that impact kind of
your decision-m?
Well, you know, so I didn't I wasn't
aware of the relationship uh initially
and when Jacobe told me and he said,
"Let me get him on the phone and I was a
little skeptical that Todd, we said,
"Let me FaceTime." I was a little
skeptical that Todd might pick up. Um I
thought it was a good litmus test and he
picked up right away and they started
talking and he said, "Guess where I am."
And he showed uh the the screen to to me
and Todd saw me and Todd said, "I'm
ironically at the airport coming to
Baltimore." And so, um, we talked after
that that for a while and it was great.
And that does carry weight. These guys
kind of know the fabric of this place
and the culture that we have here and
what's been established. And guys like
Todd were a big part of that. And so
when uh when players reach out, it means
a lot. And I've had a couple other
players reach out um tonight about the
picks, a couple guys that know some of
our guys. And that that does carry
weight because those guys have played
here. And you know, we know that um all
those guys want to see the Ravens, the
legends, they want to see us do well. So
when they endorse a player that carries
a lot of weight, [clears throat]
>> it seemed like there was a lot of
reporting about how many of the bigger
wide receivers that were in this draft
um had visited with you guys during the
pre-draft process.
>> Um was that just a coincidence or did
you kind of go into this draft wanting
to make a commitment to finding like the
ex receiver that I know you talked about
kind of wanting
>> Mar?
Um, I think that's, you know, Jonas by
design to a degree. You know, we're
trying to find different type of
players, right? You don't want to have
all big guys, all small guys, right? All
guys that play inside, all guys that can
play outside. So, the idea would be to
really build out a room that's versatile
and can do different things. and uh
Coach Doyle, I think um and uh and
Carrie Colbert, those guys did a
phenomenal job of evaluating players
this year and really presenting their
vision for what these guys could be and
and how those guys would fit and how
those guys would help us. And uh I know
that as the person that has to make the
ultimate decision, that's really really
helpful to get their input um to kind of
get a sense for how they're going to fit
and what they think they can become. And
uh you know, Jacobe was a player that I
think our coaches were excited about.
Our scouts really liked and we just
think that he's a ball of clay with a
lot of upside who has unique catching
ability and unique size. Uh then I think
that our, you know, I think Lamar's
going to like throwing the ball to him
and I think he's got a chance to really
make an impact on this team at some
point. Do you think, you know, just kind
of watching Lamar develop over his eight
years here, you know, he's typically
been a guy who's been able to find the
open guy that can get to him pretty
quickly. Uh, not a lot of like jump
balls that you see, you know, some other
quarterbacks throw. Is that kind of a
realm of his game that you are excited
to maybe open up to him with someone of
Jacob's size and speed?
>> Yeah, well, I mean, I think listen, uh,
this guy's proven. I mean, just watch
his catches. He's 6'4, over 205 lbs. He
jumps 40 in, right? That's that's not
many guys can do that unless they're
playing, you know, in the NBA. Um, he's
got great ball skills, huge hands, and
uh, you know, I think any quarterback
would like throwing a ball to a guy like
him. I think Lamar is going to be
excited when he sees him. And, uh, and I
think I think Jacobe is going to earn
the trust of Lamar, and he's he's going
to be a player that can be counted on to
make to make big plays. Jesse, what what
excites you most about Zion and the
traits that he's bringing in. What kind
of separates him from some of the other
edge rushers that you have already?
>> Yeah, Zion is a rugged, tough, physical
player. Uh, I think he's just scratching
the surface. What he can be as a player.
I think there's a ton of upside there.
Love his play style. He plays extremely
hard, plays extremely physical. um you
know is very powerful in the run game,
meaning like when he strikes blocks,
they go the other way. When people pull
on him and he strikes him, it's a it's a
train wreck. Uh he's also proven to be I
thought he made major improvements this
year as a pass rusher. Something he took
a lot of pride in this year improving in
that area. I do think he has ability to
rush up and down the line. So he's got
some versatility there, particularly as
you get into third down and you want to
put different guys in different spots.
Um, you know, you want to have different
different types of rushers. And you look
at that room now, that's a really
versatile room that I'm I couldn't be
more excited about. Uh, same thing with
the receiver room. When you talk about
Jacobe, you want guys that have
different traits, different types of
matchups. Uh, look at the DB room, the
receiver room. You want you just want
different different types of guys. You
don't want everybody to be the same. Um,
and so when you look at look at the guys
we picked up, they fit what we're trying
to do. Jesse, in the past, some of the
better Ravens teams have just been
really big, like big guys everywhere.
That was something Daniel Jeremiah was
saying at the combine that when they're
at their best, they're big everywhere.
You get Venga first round, big Z Young
obviously big, and then you get a big
receiver. Has that been not just a
receiver, but just overall across the
board, has that been a trend getting a
little bigger and more physical
throughout the roster?
>> Yeah, it's a great question. Um, you
know, I do think certain positions like
size,
uh, the traits that you're looking for
when you do look at the history of this
place and the teams that have been
really good and especially on the
defensive side of the ball, you know,
when you look at the edge guys that have
really thrived here, um, guys like that
have have been really good. Uh,
certainly on the offensive line, you
know, you're looking for a combination
of size and athleticism, uh, which we
which we definitely think Vena has. And
then as Eric mentioned, just getting a
different type of target, you know, for
Lamar, a big a big guy, a big X-T type
receiver. When you watch this guy in the
red zone make catches, you know, that's
a that's a vision that our coaches were
like, man, we could really, you know,
take advantage of that. So, um, you
know, I think you're always looking for
the best players. Often times, I do
think size, you know, is a requisite to
be a really good player. So, uh, we're
definitely always looking for the best
available. Jesse, when you think just
like how how rushers play the NFL, you
know, last year obviously you had Tulie
who doesn't have great first, but he
still was a double digit sack guy and
able to condense that pocket. Just what
do you think about that particular skill
set plays in the modern NFL?
>> Yeah, these there's a lot of quarterback
there's so many different types of
quarterbacks right now, but I would say
that one of the things that's just
showing up over and over again is these
guys' ability to extend plays and get
out of the pocket. And so you want to
have a combination of guys that can that
can win one-on-one that you can give
them some freedom and then you want the
guys that can really constrict
everything and keep them in the pocket.
And so I think we have a really good
blend now. Uh you got guys that can rush
inside and cover for some of the guys
outside that can do those different
types of things. Uh some of the stuff we
had success with the with the three or
four edges that we had last year in LA.
So again, love the look of that room.
Love what we've done to that room, you
know, in the last couple months.
um and excited to get those guys out
there and get ready to work.
>> Eric, what is um is not taking a center
to this point an indication that you
like your internal options or just you
feel good about the depth in the center
class and you feel like you get one on
day three?
>> Well, you can't make them up, right? I
mean, you can't just create a center,
Jeff, out of the sky and say, "Oh, let's
take this guy." So, you know, the board
has to fall a certain way. Um we do have
some guys we like on the third day that
we think are interesting players. Um,
couple guys got picked, right? A couple
good players. Um, but there's more
available. Um, we do have centers on the
roster. I think we got three centers on
the roster right now. So, there is going
to be a competition. Hopefully, I think
we'll have the chance to get some good
players tomorrow. Um, if if the center
ends up being the highest rated guy and
we're on the clock, then that'll be the
pick. If he's not, then that probably
won't be the pick. But, um, yeah, I
mean, it's something that, uh, you go
into the draft with a lot of different
needs. Um, we've only had three picks,
so it's kind of hard for us to fill
every single need with three picks. Uh,
I think tomorrow's a new day. We're
excited about it. I think, uh,
tomorrow's, we always call it the scouts
day because, um, we got opportunities to
kind of go after some of those guys
maybe that are under the radar. Um, I
thought last year we did a good job with
some of those guys that we took um, in
the third day and I'm confident that
we'll do the same thing again tomorrow.
>> Eric, along the same lines, there was a
bit of a run on tight ends today. Um,
what do what do you like about maybe
what's left there tomorrow?
>> Yeah, so they come in all different
shapes and sizes. You know, you got your
guys that can move a little bit, your
Hback types, you got your Y's, you got
your Fs. Um,
we are fortunate we have two, you know,
two tight ends on the roster right now
that we feel really good about. Um,
definitely would expect us to probably
draft a tight end tomorrow at some point
with eight picks. You think that we'll
have a chance to at least add one or two
guys. Uh there certainly was a run
today. Um you know, it's like uh it's a
it's a it's a blessing and a curse when
you're at 45 and uh you don't pick again
till 80. Uh you get a guy that you have
at 45, you have them as a as a first
round type of player and then you see
all these tight ends get picked between
45 and 80. So it's challenging, right?
Um, but I think we did get a playmaker
on offense and Jacobe that we're really
really excited about who brings
something different to the table and I
think our challenge tomorrow will be
able to go after other players that we
think bring something unique to the
table for us.
>> You mentioned that you heard from other
players about some of your picks. Did
you talk to Nate Wiggins before the
draft about Zion and and have you heard
from him since?
>> Uh, so I had didn't really talk to Nate
before the draft about Zion. spoke a
little bit about Clemson guys. Um I
wasn't even aware of the connection
between Zion and Nate, but I did hear
certainly hear from Nate after um after
the pick. I got a a barrage of text
messages and he's super excited. So um
it's great when you get that excitement
from your players um about players that
you're bringing in or you know, as I
said, legends of the you know, who
played here that are excited about our
players and our picks. Um, it's just I
think speaks to, you know, in some ways
the culture that we have here that, you
know, players that played here feel
comfortable reaching out to us to tell
us that they think it's a good pick or a
bad pick maybe, but the fact that they
that line of communication is open, I
think is special.
>> Eric, are you guys in as far as is Zion
in kind of wait and see mode with that
pending DWI charge? Have you gotten any
info on on where that stands? Uh yeah, I
mean we we think we do a good job uh
getting information um and uh I think
we're comfortable with it. So that's
what I would say about that.
Okay, thanks guys.
>> Thanks guys.